Abdelaziz Soliman

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

abdelaziz.soliman89@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Engineer with a background in computer engineering, transitioning from a six-year career as a maintenance engineer and serving as a reserve officer in the Armed Forces, where leadership and team management skills were developed. Dedicated over 1,000 hours to mastering software engineering, built 30+ projects, and excels in remote pair programming. I am eager to contribute my skills and passion for JavaScript, React, and PHP. Beyond coding, I enjoy reading and watching documentaries.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby on Rails, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Code Reviewing

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

November 2022 - Present

PWA Ecommerce — is a Progressive Web App (PWA) for an e-commerce platform. The application is designed to provide a seamless shopping experience across devices while leveraging modern web capabilities to ensure high performance and reliability.

- Built with: React | Laravel
- Link to Source code on GitHub | Live version of the website

Bookstore CMS — Bookstore is an online bookstore. Users can add, edit, and remove books, providing a central place to organize their work.

- Built with: React | Redux | JavaScript | Redux-thunk | React-Testing-Library | Redux-Toolkit
- Link to: Source code on GitHub | Live version of the website

Math Magicians — is a react app, allowing users to make simple calculations and read a random math-related quote.

- Built with: JavaScript, HTML5, SCSS, ReactJS, Jest, API
- Link to: Source code on GitHub | Live version of the website

Budget App — A Full-Stack mobile app where you can manage your budget to have a list of transactions associated with a category, so that you can see how much money you spent and on what. It uses a proper authentication system.

- Built with: HTML, CSS, Ruby On Rails, PostgreSQL
- Link to: Source code on GitHub | Live version of the website

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

January 2023 - Present

- Mentoring 2 junior web developers every week using Zoom and Slack, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by 90%.
- Providing advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

REALME/BBK ELECTRONICS
Maintenance Engineer

Assuit, Egypt March 2022 – October 2022

- Successfully implemented strategies that significantly lowered the bounce rate by 15%, enhancing user engagement and website performance.
- Implemented efficient processes that resulted in a remarkable improvement in the device repair rate, achieving a 20% increase within one hour, ensuring quick and reliable service.

TRANSSION HOLDINGS

Assuit, Egypt

August 2021 - March 2022

Regional Supervisor

- Established collection points, enabling me to boost both revenue and the volume of device repairs.
- Successfully achieved the target, surpassing it by an additional 7% and occasionally 10%.
- Enhanced the performance of the branches through regular and scheduled visits.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

November 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

AL-AZHAR UNIVERSITY

September 2006 - July 2011

Bachelor's degree in systems and computers Engineering.

- Obtained my Bachelor's Degree in systems and computers Engineering (GPA: 2.86)
- Developed a CMS AL-AZHAR UNIVERSITY Coordination as a final project with Oracle 10 g Developer tool,
 Employed MySQL and PostgreSQL databases for seamless data management.
- Strengthened problem-solving skills and gained a deeper understanding of challenges through coursework in Mathematics, Operating Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, C language, Databases, Numerical Analysis, and Queuing Theory.